大家好，美女们，欢迎收看这个视频。
Hello you beautiful people and welcome to this video.
您将了解如何使用非常酷的命令行程序从命令行编辑文件
You going to learn how you can edit files from the command line using a really cool command line program
叫纳诺。
called Nano.
在这段视频和下一段视频中，我将向您展示如何使用名为Nano的命令进行编辑
So in this video and the next video I'm going to show you how you can use a command called Nano to edit
并使用用户友好的命令行界面创建文件。
and create files using a user friendly command line interface.
在接下来的几个视频结束时，您将了解如何在Nano中编辑文件。
And by the end of the next few videos you're going to know how to edit files in nano.
当您将其与您到目前为止在本节中已经学到的命令相结合时，它是
And when you combine this with the commands that you've already learned so far in this section it's
很有可能您将能够在没有Linux的情况下完成许多与文件相关的任务
very likely that you'll be able to get many of your file related tasks done with Linux without ever
必须离开命令行，因此您将能够在Linux上最大限度地提高工作效率。
having to leave the command line and therefore you'll be able to maximize your productivity on Linux.
所以这会很棒的。
So this is going to be awesome.
所以，让我们继续直截了当地谈吧。
So let's go ahead and get right into it.
好的。
All right.
在这节课中，我们将使用Nano命令创建一个名为Diary Datti ex-state的文件。
So in this lecture we're going to make a file called Diary Datti ex-state using the Nano command.
现在日记Datti X-C文件实际上还不存在，但是没关系。
Now the diary Datti X-C file doesn't actually exist yet but that's OK.
我们也可以使用Nano创建文件。
We can also create the file using nano.
如果我们输入not，让我们先转到桌面，然后如果我们输入nano
So if we type not let's go to the desktop first let's head over to the desktop and then if we type nano
日记，XTi博士，好的，我按Enter键。
diary Dr XTi OK and I press enter.
您会注意到，我们的终端已经更改了外观，实际上我们现在正在编辑一个名为diry的文件
You'll notice that our terminal has changed its look and we're actually now editing a file called diry
正如你在顶部看到的那样，这需要胶带。
that takes tape as you can see at the top.
在Nano编辑器中，您可以在这里看到Nano2.0版本8.6。
In the Nano editor as you can see here nano version 2.0 eight point six.
显然现在我们可以在这里打任何我们想打的东西了。
Apparently now we can type what ever we want in here.
例如，我可以输入hello，我的名字是Ziyad，我教Linux和Python课程等等。
So for example I could type hello my name is Ziyad and I teach Linux and Python courses and more.
好的。
OK.
它的工作原理与您以前使用过的任何其他图形文本编辑器一样。
And it works just like any other graphical text editor that you've ever used before.
您可以直接在shell中输入。
And you can just type directly there in the shell.
现在在底部，您可以看到实际上有一个小工具栏，它告诉您一些事情
Now down the bottom you can see that there's actually a little toolbar that tells you some of the things
在Nano中可以做到这一点，选项在白色方块中，然后以键盘快捷键的形式出现
that you can do in nano and the options are in the white squares and then in the form of keyboard shortcuts
单人纸牌，你必须看一看。
solitaire you have to read them.
好的。
OK.
所以在Nano中，你在这里看到的小箭头，小帽子或胡萝卜符号意味着控制
So in nano The little arrowhead that you see here the little hat or the carrot symbol means the control
键盘上的键。
key on your keyboard.
例如，我们在这里使用了get help命令来获取帮助。
So for example here we have the GET HELP command over to get help.
我猜是工具栏上的选项，给出了这个快捷方式，这里有箭头，然后
I guess option from the toolbar and it's given this this shortcut here it's got the arrow head and then
A大写G。
a capital G.
所以，如果我们按键盘上的Ctrl键，然后按g键，这就是我们要做的，就是控制Engy
So if we press control on our keyboard and press g which is exactly what we do is just control Engy
一起执行该命令，我们可以在这里看到，现在在Get Help菜单中
together that executes that command and we can see here that we have now when in the Get Help menu and
我们可以向下滚动，看到一些有关使用Nano的帮助。
we can scroll down and see some help about using nano.
好的。
OK.
我们在这里可以看到有一些要关闭，我们需要按Ctrl键和X键，因为您
And we can see here that there's some to close this we would need to press control and X because you
可以看到这个小箭头，然后X服务器控制着X Chewbacca，我们又开始写了。
can see the little arrow and then an X server was controlling X Chewbacca there and we're back writing.
好的。
OK.
我们也可以关闭Nano，例如，通过按Ctrl和X，它会说您想说是还是
We can also close Nano for example by pressing control an X and it will say do you want to say yes or
不，让我们按控件单击取消，然后看看我们都被取消了，我们还在继续。
no let's just click cancel by control and see that we are both canceled we're still back in.
好的。
OK.
那么我们怎么才能挽救这个。
So how would we save this.
我们如何将此diry directX t保存到桌面上的主文件夹词汇表中对不起，因为您可以
How do we save this diry directx t in in our home folder glossary on our desktop sorry because you can
看这上面，店面上说我们在我们的桌面上。
see up here shopfront says that we're in our desktop.
要在Nano中做到这一点，您需要使用正确的函数。
Well to do that in nano you would use the right function.
因此，写文件是一种奇特的方式，意思是保存文件，因此保存和写入基本上是一样的
So writing a file is a fancy way of saying saving a file so saving and writing are basically the same
一件事。
thing.
所以要写一个文件，我们需要按下Ctrl键，哦，所以我们得到了箭头，小克拉符号
And so to write a file we need to press control and oh so we've got the arrow the little carat symbol
这里的意思是控制键和哦。
here which means the control key and oh.
所以这意味着我们已经失去了控制。
So that means we've lost control.
哦，现在它问我们要保存什么，让我们将其保存为日记，然后按Enter键
Oh and now it's asking us what do you want to save as let's save it as diary takes t and we press enter
它会说它写了三行，但我们在这里可以看到，我们实际上已经得到了Dry dot Txi镜头。
it will say it wrote three lines but we can see here that we've actually got diry dot TXI takes.
如果我们在任何其他数据中打开该文件，我们可以看到该文件确实已创建。
If we open that in any other data we can see that that file has indeed been created.
所以我可以在这里写一些东西，我可以说，就像你知道的，比如杰克和吉尔上了
So I could write something in here I could say like you know something like Jack and Jill went up the
小山。
hill.
好的，然后按CONTROL键，再按ENTER键。
All right and then press control and press enter.
如果我按下CONTROL，它就消失了。
And if I press control an x x it OK it's gone away.
但如果我看一下糖尿病患者的内部，杰克和吉尔上山的数据就是救命稻草。
But if I look inside diabetic's a save that data in that Jack and Jill went up the hill.
因此，Nano是一个文本编辑器，可以通过命令行控制。
So it's the Nano is a text editor that you can control from the command line.
这不是令人难以置信吗。
So isn't that incredible.
您现在可以编辑文件，而无需加载图形密集型编辑器。
You can now edit files without needing to load up graphically intensive editors.
此外，使用这样的文件几乎可以在任何地方工作，即使您可以远程访问
And plus working with files like this will work pretty much anywhere even if you have remotely access
到可能没有安装图形用户界面的服务器。
to a server that might not have a graphical user interface installed.
Nano等文本编辑器仍可使用。
Text editors such as Nano will still work.
那么纳米还能做些什么呢？
So what other things can nano do.
好的，让我们用我们的方式来选择。
Well let's just work our way across the options.
现在我们已经了解了如何获取帮助，如何退出使用Control和X，以及如何使用
Now we've seen how to get help how to quit using control and X and how to write or save files using
管制编号
control no.
下面的Lead文件选项怎么样？控件和我们的可读性良好的文件允许您获取内容
What about the lead file option down here the control and our well read file allows you to get content
从另一个文件中取出，然后将其放入这个文件中。
from another file and basically place it inside of this one.
所以如果我返回到我们的shell，如果我们退出，我们尝试创建一个写有生日快乐的文件，我们
So if I head back to our shell if we exit and we try to create a file that says happy birthday and we
将“生日快乐”放入名为“生日聚会X-C”的文件中，我们可以看到已经创建了生日聚会XTi。
echo happy birthday into a file called birthday party X-C we see the birthday party XTi has been created.
如果我们重新打开，日记本拿起茶，我们走到底部，按下Ctrl键，
If we are back open up again the diary takes tea and we head down the bottom and we press control and
我们在中的控制是完全读取文件，它会告诉您要插入哪个文件。
our control in our is full read file and it's going to say which file do you want to insert.
注意它说的是来自点劈开。
And notice it says from dot slash.
这意味着从这个目录。
That means from this directory.
好的。
OK.
那么让我们试着把它卖了吧。
So let's let's try and sell it.
所以你实际插入的是他生日的数据。
So the one you actually insert data from his birthday.
xti.
XTi.
如果我按Enter键，您可以看到刚刚插入了“生日快乐”。
And if I press enter you can see that happy birthday has just been inserted.
这样就开始读取文件了，那么“在哪里”选项呢？
So that started reading files What about the where is option.
WHERE IS选项是CONTROL和W，它所做的基本上是在您的文件中搜索单词。
Well the where is option is control and W and what that does is basically search for words in your file.
因此，如果我们返回到文件的顶部，然后按Ctrl和W，现在我们就可以搜索单词了
So if we head back up to the top of the file and we press control and W now we can search for words
搜索生日这个词。
that search for the word birthday.
因此，如果我们键入生日并按Enter键，我们现在可以看到Nano已经将我们跳到单词
So if we type birthday and press Enter we now see that Nano has jumped us right down to where the word
生日开始了。
birthday starts.
这样我们就可以从那里开始编辑了。
And so we can edit it from there on.
现在，缺省情况下，WHERE IS选项搜索在文件中转发，并且它在不区分大小写的情况下进行搜索
Now by default the where is option search is forward in a file and it searches in a case insensitive
举止。
manner.
所以这意味着大写和小写都无关紧要。
So that means that uppercase and lowercase don't matter.
所以如果我在这里搜索生日或者大写字母。
So if I went up here and I searched for birthday or in uppercase.
实际上，您可以注意到，它会预先显示您搜索的内容。
Actually you can notice that it shows you what you search beforehand.
所以我要把这两个字母都用大写，我们可以看到这实际上并不重要。
So I'm just going to put both in uppercase we can see that it actually didn't matter.
它发现了生日，即使它出生的时候都是小写的，所以研究大小写不敏感的地方
And it found birthday even though birth it was all in lowercase So where researches in a case insensitive
方式和/或默认情况下搜索为正向。
manner and or by default search is forward.
但是如果我们向下到文件的底部，如果我们向下移动并再次使用控件w，您可以
But if we had down to the bottom of the files if we shift down here and use control w again you can
向下看，如果我最大化屏幕，可能会更清楚地看到，实际上
see down the bottom if I maximize the screen maybe it makes it a bit clearer that there are actually
还会弹出其他选项。
other options that pop up as well.
好的。
OK.
现在，这些选项中有一些以胡萝卜符号心开头，意思是控制键
Now some of these options begin with the the carrot symbol the heart which means the control key but
有些人从这个开始。
some start with this.
M减去。
M minus.
好的，你可以看到em减去C减去或减去B减去J。
OK you can see em minus C minus or minus B minus J.
那么没有负号的负号是什么意思。
So what's the minus mean without minus.
代表修改。
Stands for modify.
这通常是键盘上的Alt键，所以HLT键，所以您可以在这里看到
And this is usually the alt key on your keyboard so the HLT key so you can see here that we've got the
M和减去C选项，表示区分大小写。
M and minus C option which stands for case sensitive.
所以如果我们的媒体Alton‘s See，你可以看到它已经改变了，所以我们现在正在搜索一个案例
So if our press Alton's see you can see now that it has changed so that we are now searching in a case
敏感的方式。
sensitive way.
好的，如果我现在搜索，请稍等，因为这只是向前搜索，所以我
OK so if I now search for actually hold on as well because this is only going a search forward so I
如果我按ALT并且也要向后搜索，就可以。
can if I press alt and be to search backwards as well.
当我开始搜索区分大小写和向后搜索大写的生日时，我会发现什么都没有
When I begin to search case sensitive and backwards for birthday in uppercase I will see that nothing
被发现了。
was found.
您看，但是如果您只喜欢控件，并且您看到它已保存，那么我们的设置将是大小写的
You see but if all you do just like the control and you see it saved our settings is going to be case
敏感的和倒数的，生日都是小写的，我们看到那已经找到了。
sensitive and backwards benefices birthday all lowercase we see that that has been found.
好的。
OK.
所以这是相当了不起的，对吧。
So that that's quite awesome right.
您还可以修改这些命令的行为方式。
You can also modify the way that these commands behave.
所以如果你看到m减去，那就意味着按键盘上的旧键，hlt键。
So if you see m minus that means press the old key the HLT key on your keyboard.
如果你看到这个三角形，我们有一个小箭头，它是键盘上的控制键，
And if you see the triangle we have the little arrowhead That's the control key on your keyboard and
这几乎涵盖了您在Nano中要做的所有事情。
that will cover pretty much everything that you'll do in nano.
所以我们还是回到我们正常的菜单吧。
So let's just head back to our normal menu here.
因此，为了节省时间，我们将在这里剪下这段视频，然后在
So in the interests of time we're going to cut the video here and we're going to pick it right up in
下一个视频。
the next video.
我们将浏览您在Nano中提供的选项的睡觉。
We will go through the rest of the options that you have in nano.
所以我希望这对您有用，您已经看到Nano是一个文本编辑器，您可以通过命令打开它
So I hope this was useful you've seen that nano is a text editor that you can open from your command
这一行允许您在不离开命令行的情况下执行所有文件编辑工作。
line that allows you to do all your file editing stuff without ever leaving the command line.
所以我只能说，嘿，我们有了dormi，它需要一天的时间才能做出一些改变，省去它x。
So I can just say hey we've got dormi that takes day at it to make some changes save it x.
我们又回到了命令行，因此它为您提供了一种非常好的编辑文件和恢复文件的方式
And we're back in the command line so it gives you a really nice way of editing files and getting back
你的所作所为。
to what you were doing.
所以让我们干脆把出口去掉，比如说把屏幕清空，然后我们就可以继续我们的工作了。
So let's just get rid of say the exit clear the screen and we're good to go continue on with our work.
因此，让我们在下一个视频中继续这一点，看看Nano提供的其他选择。
So let's pick this up in the next video to take a look at the other options that Nano has to offer.